<innhold>
    <lesmer intro="Where can I find information about my case?">
    <avsnitt>You can log in to <lenke url="https://foreldrepenger.nav.no" ekstern="true">Your parental allowance</lenke> and see the status of your application. You can also submit application attachments.</avsnitt>
    </lesmer>
    <lesmer intro="When will I get a response to my application?">
         <avsnitt>The earliest you will receive a response to your application is <b>4 weeks</b> the start of your parental benefit period. This is because we use the most recent information about your income when we calculate how much parental benefit you will receive.</avsnitt>
    </lesmer>
    <lesmer intro="Utbetalingsdato">
        <avsnitt>Perantal benefit is paid out by the 25th of the month. You see how much perantal benefit you get paid on your NAV, under <lenke url="https://tjenester.nav.no/dittnav/oversikt" ekstern="true">the payout schedule.</lenke> If you receive parental benefit from your employer, you must contact the employer for the pay date and payout schedule.</avsnitt>
    </lesmer>
    <lesmer intro="Can I receive parental benefit while I am a student?">
        <avsnitt>To be entitled to parental benefit, you must have had income in six of the past 10 months. Student loans and grants from the Norwegian State Educational Loan Fund ("Lånekassen") do not provide entitlement to parental benefit. If you are not entitled to parental benefit, you can apply for a lump-sum grant. Try our <lenke url="/veiviser">"veiviser"</lenke> to see what you may be entitled to.</avsnitt>
    </lesmer>
    <lesmer intro="I receive benefits from NAV. Am I entitled to receive parental benefit?">
        <avsnitt>If you are receiving one of the following benefits from NAV, you may be entitled to parental benefit:</avsnitt>
        <liste>
            <punkt>Sickness benefit</punkt>
            <punkt>Parental benefit </punkt>
            <punkt>Pregnancy benefit</punkt>
            <punkt>Work assessment allowance (AAP)</punkt>
            <punkt>Unemployment benefit</punkt>
            <punkt>Care benefit, attendance allowance or training allowance</punkt>
        </liste>
        <avsnitt>Are you unsure of what you may be entitled to?<lenke url="https://familie.nav.no/veiviser" ekstern="true">Use the wizard to find out what you are entitled to.</lenke></avsnitt>
    </lesmer>
    <lesmer intro="What is the difference between parental benefit and lump-sum grant?">
        <avsnitt>Parental benefit provides you with income while you are at home with your child. Lump-sum grant is benefit paid out as a single lump sum to people who are expecting a child and have not had income in the past year. You can choose to receive a lump-sum grant even if you are entitled to parental benefit, but you can only receive one of these benefits.</avsnitt>
        <avsnitt>Are you unsure of what you may be entitled to?<lenke url="https://familie.nav.no/veiviser" ekstern="true">Use the wizard to find out what you are entitled to.</lenke></avsnitt>
    </lesmer>
    <lesmer intro="What is the difference between the parental benefit period and the shared period?">
        <avsnitt>The parental benefit period is the entire period during which parental benefit is paid. When both parents are entitled to parental benefit, the parental benefit period consists of 3 weeks of parental benefit for the mother before delivery, a maternal quota, a paternal quota and a shared period.</avsnitt>
        <avsnitt>You can use our <lenke url="https://foreldrepengeplanlegger.nav.no/foreldrepengeplanlegger" ekstern="true">parental benefit planner</lenke> to plan how long you can stay at home with your child.</avsnitt>
    </lesmer>
    <lesmer intro="I am going to take unpaid leave">
        <avsnitt>You must arrange unpaid leave with your employer. You cannot postpone when you receive parental benefit if you are on unpaid leave. The other parent may postpone their parental benefit on grounds of full-time work, illness or holiday in the period you are on unpaid leave. You can use our <lenke url="https://foreldrepengeplanlegger.nav.no/foreldrepengeplanlegger" ekstern="true"> parental benefit planner</lenke> to plan how long you can stay at home with your child.</avsnitt>
        <avsnitt>Unpaid leave may affect your entitlement to other NAV benefits and accumulation of rights to parental benefit for new children. <lenke url="https://www.nav.no/no/Person/Arbeid/Sykmeldt%2C+arbeidsavklaringspenger+og+yrkesskade/Sykepenger/Sykepenger+til+sarskilte+grupper#chapter-5" ekstern="true">Read more about your rights here.</lenke></avsnitt>
    </lesmer>
    <avsnitt type="undertittel" class="center top-spacing">Didn’t find what you were looking for?</avsnitt>
    <avsnitt class="center">Contact us on:</avsnitt>
</innhold>
