<innhold>
    <lesmer intro="When will I get a response to my application?">
         <avsnitt>The earliest you will receive a response to your application is 4 weeks the start of your parental benefit period. This is because we use the most recent information about your income when we calculate how much parental benefit you will receive.</avsnitt
    </lesmer>
    <lesmer intro="Can I receive parental benefit while I am a student?">
        <avsnitt>To be entitled to parental benefit, you must have had income in six of the past ten months. Student loans and grants from the Norwegian State Educational Loan Fund ("Lånekassen") do not provide entitlement to parental benefit. If you are not entitled to parental benefit, you can apply for a lump-sum grant. Try our <lenke url="/veiviser">"veiviser"</lenke> to see what you may be entitled to.</avsnitt>
    </lesmer>
    <lesmer intro="I receive benefits from NAV. Am I entitled to receive parental benefit?">
        <avsnitt>If you are receiving one of the following benefits from NAV, you may be entitled to parental benefit:</avsnitt>
        <liste>
            <punkt>Sickness benefit</punkt>
            <punkt>Parental benefit </punkt>
            <punkt>Pregnancy benefit</punkt>
            <punkt>Work assessment allowance (AAP)</punkt>
            <punkt>Unemployment benefit</punkt>
            <punkt>Care benefit, attendance allowance or training allowance</punkt>
        </liste>
    </lesmer>
    <lesmer intro="What is the difference between parental benefit and lump-sum grant?">
        <avsnitt>Parental benefit provides you with income while you are at home with your child. Lump-sum grant is benefit paid out as a single lump sum to people who are expecting a child and have not had income in the past year. You can choose to receive a lump-sum grant even if you are entitled to parental benefit, but you can only receive one of these benefits.</avsnitt>
    </lesmer>
    <lesmer intro="What is the difference between the parental benefit period and the shared period?">
        <avsnitt>The parental benefit period is the entire period during which parental benefit is paid. When both parents are entitled to parental benefit, the parental benefit period consists of three weeks of parental benefit for the mother before delivery, a maternal quota, a paternal quota and a shared period.</avsnitt>
    </lesmer>
    <lesmer intro="I have submitted an application, but cannot find it on Dine Foreldrepenger">
        <avsnitt>If the mother’s or the father’s parental benefit period started in 2018 or earlier, it may take <b>up to three weeks</b> before your application is registered with us and visible on <lenke url="https://foreldrepenger.nav.no" ekstern="true">Dine Foreldrepenger ("Your Parental Benefit")</lenke>. When you submitted the application, you received a receipt confirming that we have received it.</avsnitt>
    </lesmer>
    <lesmer intro="I am going to take unpaid leave">
        <avsnitt>You must arrange unpaid leave with your employer. You cannot postpone when you receive parental benefit if you are on unpaid leave. The other parent may postpone their parental benefit on grounds of full-time work, illness or holiday in the period you are on unpaid leave. </avsnitt>
        <avsnitt>Unpaid leave may affect your entitlement to other NAV benefits and accumulation of rights to parental benefit for new children. <lenke url="https://www.nav.no/no/Person/Arbeid/Sykmeldt%2C+arbeidsavklaringspenger+og+yrkesskade/Sykepenger/Sykepenger+til+sarskilte+grupper#chapter-5" ekstern="true">Read more about your rights here.</lenke></avsnitt>
    </lesmer>
    <avsnitt type="undertittel" class="center top-spacing">Didn’t find what you were looking for?</avsnitt>
    <avsnitt class="center">Contact us on:</avsnitt>
</innhold>
