<innhold>
    <lesmer intro="Length of postponement using annual leave">
        <avsnitt>You can apply to postpone your parental benefit period by taking annual leave (holiday) for up to four weeks and one day for each calendar year. In addition, you can postpone by using remaining holiday days from the previous calendar year and you can take up to ten holiday days in advance from the coming year. Only the statutory part of your annual leave entitles you to postpone the parental benefit period.</avsnitt>
        <avsnitt>Statutory holiday means holiday (annual leave) pursuant to the Norwegian Holiday Act. Public holidays are not considered statutory holiday (annual leave), and you cannot postpone your parental benefit due to holiday on public holidays. If there are public holidays during the period you have taken annual leave, you will be paid parental benefit for these days.</avsnitt>

    </lesmer>
    <lesmer intro="You can postpone using the following process">
        <liste>
            <punkt>Arrange with your <b>employer</b> as to when you will take holidays.</punkt>
            <punkt>Your employer confirms your holiday in the <lenke url="https://www.nav.no/inntektsmelding" ekstern="true">income statement</lenke> that they send to NAV.</punkt>
            <punkt>In the <b>parental benefit application</b>, you specify that you are <b>postponing</b> the period because you are having a holiday</punkt>
            <punkt>If you do not know when you will be taking holidays when you apply, you can send an application at <lenke url="https://www.foreldrepenger.nav.no/" ekstern="true">Your Parental Benefit</lenke> to postpone at a later date.</punkt>
        </liste>
        <avsnitt><b>Deadline</b>: You have to apply <b>before</b> you start your holiday.</avsnitt>
    </lesmer>
    <avsnitt className="top-spacing" type="undertittel">Holiday pay from the parental benefit</avsnitt>
    <avsnitt>If you are an employee, you are entitled to holiday pay from the parental benefit. If your employer is paying you salary during your period of leave, the holiday pay is paid to your employer. </avsnitt>
    <avsnitt>The holiday pay amounts to 10.2 per cent of what is paid out before tax in the first 12 or 15 weeks of the parental benefit period. </avsnitt>
</innhold>