<innhold>
    <avsnitt class="blokk-m">If you want to stay home with the child at the same time or take turns, you have several options.</avsnitt>
    <lesmer intro="One is at home full-time, the other for up to 50 per cent">
        <avsnitt>If one parent draws full parental benefit from their quota, both parents can stay at home at the same time for up to 150 per cent of the time from week seven after the child was born. The first 6 weeks are reserved for the mother for medical reasons.</avsnitt>
        <avsnitt>Example: The father draws 100 per cent benefit from the paternal quota during the same period that the mother is working 50 per cent and drawing 50 per cent benefit from the shared period.</avsnitt>
        <avsnitt>Remember, you must each submit your <lenke url="https://foreldrepengesoknad.nav.no" ekstern="true">application for parental benefit.</lenke></avsnitt>
    </lesmer>
    <lesmer intro="Take turns being a home">
        <avsnitt>Parents can take turns at staying at home and working starting from week 7 after the child was born. The first 6 weeks are reserved for the mother for medical reasons.</avsnitt>
        <avsnitt>If you would like to take turns staying at home and working for a period, you can combine parental benefit with part-time work. Together you will receive full parental benefit.</avsnitt>
        <avsnitt>If the father or co-mother is going to draw parental benefit from the shared period, there are activity requirements for the mother during this period. This means that the mother must work or have some other approved activity during this period.</avsnitt>
        <avsnitt>Example: The father wants to draw 50 per cent parental benefit from the shared period during the same period that the mother is also drawing 50 per cent parental benefit.  In this case, the mother must work 50 per cent during this period, to meet the activity requirement.</avsnitt>
        <avsnitt>Remember, you must each submit your <lenke url="https://foreldrepengesoknad.nav.no" ekstern="true">application for parental benefit.</lenke></avsnitt>
    </lesmer>
    <lesmer intro="When you have twins or multiple children">
        <avsnitt>Parents who have more than one child at the same time receive more weeks of parental benefit that they can share between them. These extra weeks are called “multiple children weeks” and can be taken at any time during the parental benefit period. The parents can take them at the same time or separately. There is no requirement regarding what the mother is doing when the father or co-mother is taking days from the multiple children weeks.</avsnitt>
        <liste>
            <punkt><b>Twins:</b> You will receive 17 extra weeks at 100 per cent parental benefit and 21 extra weeks at 80 per cent parental benefit.</punkt>
            <punkt><b>3 or more children:</b> You will receive 46 extra weeks at 100 per cent parental benefit and 56 extra weeks at 80 per cent parental benefit.</punkt>
        </liste>
        <avsnitt><b>Adopting</b></avsnitt>
        <avsnitt>Parents who adopt more than one child at the same time receive more weeks of parental benefit that they can share between them. These extra weeks are called “multiple children weeks” and can be taken at any time during the parental benefit period. The parents can take them at the same time or separately. There is no requirement regarding what the mother is doing when the father or co-mother is taking days from the multiple children weeks.</avsnitt>
        <liste>
        <punkt>If you adopt 2 children, you will receive 17 extra weeks at 100 per cent parental benefit and 21 extra weeks at 80 per cent parental benefit</punkt>
        <punkt>If you adopt 3 or more children, you will receive 46 extra weeks at 100 per cent parental benefit and 56 extra weeks at 80 per cent parental benefit.</punkt>
        </liste>
        <avsnitt><b>If only one parent is entitled to parental benefit</b></avsnitt>
        <avsnitt>If only one of the parents is entitled to parental benefit, this parent is also entitled to all the multiple children weeks. There is no requirement regarding what the mother is doing when the father or co-mother is taking days from the multiple children weeks.</avsnitt>
        <avsnitt>The father or co-mother is also entitled to all the multiple children weeks if the mother is receiving disability benefit.</avsnitt>
    </lesmer>
    <lesmer intro="Fathers and co-mothers are entitled to two weeks leave after the child is born">
        <avsnitt>The father or co-mother is entitled to leave for 2 weeks after the child is born. This is laid down in the Norwegian Working Environment Act. Since these 2 weeks are not part of the parental benefit period from NAV, you need to ask your employer or contact the Norwegian Labour Inspection Authority if you have any questions.</avsnitt>
    </lesmer>
    <lesmer intro="Unpaid leave and holiday">
        <avsnitt>If both parents want to stay at home at the same time when the father or co-mother is taking their quota, the mother can take unpaid leave or annual leave (holiday).</avsnitt>
        <avsnitt>The father or co-mother may also take unpaid leave or holiday while the mother is receiving parental benefit. You can use our <lenke url="https://foreldrepengeplanlegger.nav.no/foreldrepengeplanlegger" ekstern="true"> parental benefit planner</lenke> to plan how long you can stay at home with your child.</avsnitt>
        <avsnitt>This is a matter you must agree with your employer and is not part of the parental benefit period from NAV. Unpaid leave may affect your entitlement to other NAV benefits and accumulation of rights to parental benefit for new children. <lenke url="https://www.nav.no/no/Person/Arbeid/Sykmeldt%2C+arbeidsavklaringspenger+og+yrkesskade/Sykepenger/Sykepenger+til+sarskilte+grupper#chapter-5" ekstern="true">Read more about your rights here.</lenke></avsnitt>
    </lesmer>
</innhold>
