<innhold>
    <avsnitt>If you want to stay home with the child at the same time or take turns, you have several options.</avsnitt>
    <lesmer intro="One is at home full-time, the other for up to 50 per cent">
        <avsnitt>One of you can be at home and receive 100 per cent parental benefit from his/her quota. The other can combine partial work with up to 50 per cent parental benefit from the joint part. You will therefore together receive up to 150 per cent parental benefit.</avsnitt>
    </lesmer>
    <lesmer intro="Take turns being a home">
        <avsnitt>If you would like to take turns being at home and at work, you can combine the parental benefit with partial work at the same time. You will then together receive the full parental benefit.</avsnitt>
        <avsnitt>If the father wants to take 50 per cent of the parental benefit <b>fra fellesperioden</b> at the same time as the mother is taking 50 per cent, the mother must satisfy 50 per cent of the activity requirement. She can do this by working 50 per cent. </avsnitt>
        <avsnitt>If you would like to combine the parental benefit at the same time, the parental benefit cannot be more than 100 per cent in total. Remember that you both have to apply.</avsnitt>
    </lesmer>
    <lesmer intro="When you have twins or multiple children">
        <avsnitt>You can take the extra weeks at the same time at any stage during the parental benefit period. When only the father or co-mother is entitled to the parental benefit, the weeks can be taken at the same time that the mother is at home.</avsnitt>
        <liste>
            <punkt>If the mother takes the multi-child weeks, the father cannot receive the parental benefit from the joint period at the same time.</punkt>
            <punkt>If the father takes the multi-child weeks, the mother cannot take the joint period at the same time. There are no requirements for what the father has to do when the mother takes the parental benefit from the joint period. </punkt>
        </liste>
    </lesmer>
    <lesmer intro="Parental leave">
        <avsnitt>The father or co-mother is entitled to two weeks of leave with the mother when the child is born. This is stipulated in the Working Environment Act, but is not part of the parental benefit period from NAV. You must therefore ask your employer or contact the Norwegian Labour Inspection Authority if you have any queries.</avsnitt>
    </lesmer>
</innhold>