<innhold>
    <avsnitt>As a father or co-mother, you can begin your parental benefit period from <b>week 7</b> after birth. If you are adopting, the parental benefit period will commence <b>when care of the child is assumed</b>.</avsnitt>
    <avsnitt>If you adopt from abroad, you can choose if you would like to start receiving the parental benefit when you assume care of the child while abroad, or the day you arrive in Norway with the child.</avsnitt>
    <avsnitt>If you start later, you will receive fewer weeks of the parental benefit if you do not apply for a postponement.</avsnitt>
    <avsnitt>If it is not convenient to take full leave from work, you can take your parental benefit in combination with partial work or postpone because you are working fulltime.</avsnitt>
    <avsnitt type="element">Activity requirement for the mother</avsnitt>
    <avsnitt>Both when you take the parental benefit or postpone this, the mother must either</avsnitt>
    <liste>
        <punkt>be working</punkt>
        <punkt>studying full-time</punkt>
        <punkt>combining study with work that together makes it full-time</punkt>
        <punkt>be fully dependent on assistance to take care of the child due to sickness</punkt>
        <punkt>participating in a qualification programme</punkt>
        <punkt>participating fulltime in the Introduction Programme for newly arrived immigrants pursuant to chapter 2 of the Introduction Act</punkt>
    </liste>
    <avsnitt>Read more about <lenke url="https://familie.nav.no/om-foreldrepenger" ekstern="false">the entire application process.</lenke></avsnitt>
    <lesmer intro="Is the mother receiving disability benefit?">
    <avsnitt>If the mother is receiving <b>disability benefit</b>, you may take up to 15 weeks at 100 per cent parental benefit, or 19 weeks at 80 per cent parental benefit without the mother having an activity requirement. These weeks must be taken before 46 weeks after the child was born if you choose 100 per cent parental benefit, or 56 weeks after the child was born if you choose 80 per cent parental benefit. If you are taking more than these weeks, the mother must be working, studying or in another approved activity when you are at home with the child or if you are postponing parental benefit.</avsnitt>
    <avsnitt>If the father is to postpone the parental benefit period or work part-time, he must apply for this while there are still 15 or 19 weeks of the period of 46 or 56 weeks after taking over the care. If the father applies at a later date, he loses the number of days he applies late. If the father applies after 46 or 56 weeks, he will be denied. When the father postpones, the mother must be at work, studying or in another approved activity. There is no requirement for the mother's activity when the father is to take the period he has postponed.</avsnitt>
    </lesmer>
</innhold>