<innhold>
    <avsnitt class="blokk-m">Accumulating rights to the parental benefit is the same as for the birth of a child. The same applies to the calculation of the parental benefit.</avsnitt>
    <lesmer intro="When does the parental benefit period commence?">
        <avsnitt>If you adopt from abroad, you can select when you would like to start receiving the parental benefit:</avsnitt>
        <liste>
            <punkt>when you assume care of the child while abroad</punkt>
            <punkt>the day you arrive in Norway with the child. If you start later, you will receive fewer weeks.</punkt>
        </liste>
        <avsnitt>You may choose yourselves as to who will start be home during the period of leave. When the father shall receive the parental benefit from the joint period, the rules as for birth apply and there are <lenke url="#hvor-lenge-kan-du-fa-foreldrepenger">activity requirements</lenke> for the mother.</avsnitt>
    </lesmer>
    <lesmer intro="How long can you receive the parental benefit?">
        <avsnitt>The parental benefit period is 46 weeks if you select 100 per cent parental benefit or 56 weeks at 80 per cent parental benefit.</avsnitt>
        <avsnitt>The weeks are shared between the parents in the same manner as the parental benefit in connection with birth.<lenke url="#hvor-lenge-kan-du-fa-foreldrepenger">the parental benefit in connection with birth.</lenke></avsnitt>
    </lesmer>
    <lesmer intro="Are you adopting more than one child?">
        <avsnitt>If you adopt more than one child at the same time, you will receive more weeks of parental benefit. These extra weeks are called “multiple children weeks” and can be taken at any time during the parental benefit period. The parents can take them at the same time or separately. There is no requirement regarding what the mother is doing when the father or co-mother is taking days from the multiple children weeks.</avsnitt>
        <liste>
            <punkt>If you adopt <b>2 children</b>, you will receive 17 extra weeks at 100 per cent parental benefit and 21 extra weeks at 80 per cent parental benefit.</punkt>
            <punkt>If you adopt <b>3 or more children</b>, you will receive 46 extra weeks at 100 per cent parental benefit and 56 extra weeks at 80 per cent parental benefit.</punkt>
        </liste>
        <avsnitt>Remember, you must each submit your <lenke url="https://foreldrepengesoknad.nav.no" ekstern="true">application for parental benefit.</lenke></avsnitt>
    </lesmer>
    <lesmer intro="Adoption that does not entitle one to the parental benefit">
        <avsnitt>You are not entitled to the parental benefit if the child you adopt is over the age of 15 or is the child of your spouse.</avsnitt>
    </lesmer>
    <lesmer intro="Adoption of stepchild">
        <avsnitt>You are entitled to the parental benefit if you adopt your stepchild during the parental benefit period.</avsnitt>
    </lesmer>
</innhold>