<innhold>
    <avsnitt>Your parental benefit will normally be calculated based on your average income of the <b>last 3 calendar months</b> before the start of your parental benefit period.</avsnitt>
    <avsnitt>If you start by postponing your parental benefit period, your parental benefit will normally be calculated based on your average income the last 3 calendar months before the postponing starts.</avsnitt>
    <avsnitt>This calculation applies regardless of whether you are employed in a permanent position or have varying periods of work or income</avsnitt>
    <avsnitt>If there is a difference of more than 25 per cent between your annual income and your income for the last 3 months, we have to determine which income is most representative of your situation.</avsnitt>
    <liste>
        <punkt>If your employment has lasted for <b>less than 3 months</b>, your parental benefit shall be calculated based on the income have had during the period in which you have been working. Your income will be converted into a monthly income.</punkt>
        <punkt>If you have had <b>holiday</b> or short periods of random <b>unpaid leave</b> during the period in which you have had an income, your income will be determined on the basis of what you would normally have had if you had been working.</punkt>
        <punkt>If your <b>employment ends</b> before you start your parental benefit period and you have no other work or benefits from NAV, your parental benefit will be calculated on the basis of your income for the last 3 months before the employment relationship ended.</punkt>
    </liste>
    <avsnitt>If you are both <b>employed and work freelance</b>, your earnings will be calculated separately and then added together to give a single figure. If you have a total income of over 6 times the National Insurance basic amount ("G"), your income as an employee will be used as the calculation basis.</avsnitt>
    <avsnitt>If you are both <b>self-employed and a freelancer or employed</b>, your parental benefit will be calculated based on both of your incomes. Your freelance income will always be used as the basis for calculation. Freelance income up to 6 times the National Insurance basic amount ("G") is always covered in full.</avsnitt>
    <avsnitt class="blokk-l">Unsure whether you are self-employed, freelancer or employee? <lenke url="https://www.nav.no/no/person/innhold-til-person-forside/nyttig-a-vite/er-jeg-selvstendig-naeringsdrivende-frilanser-eller-arbeidstaker" ekstern="true">Click here for guidance</lenke></avsnitt>
    <lesmer intro="Income included in the calculation">
        <liste>
            <punkt>Earned income and benefits that are equivalent to earned income.</punkt>
            <punkt>Remuneration from own work efforts, for example, bonus and fees you have received</punkt>
            <punkt>Non-cash benefits that you receive, for example free car, mobile telephone and internet, if these are lost during the parental benefit period.</punkt>
        </liste>
    </lesmer>
    <lesmer intro="Income that is not included">
        <liste>
            <punkt>Overtime pay</punkt>
            <punkt>Holiday pay</punkt>
            <punkt>Allowances that cover expenses in connection with your work, for example, daily allowance, car allowance, tool allowance and nuisance bonus.</punkt>
        </liste>
    </lesmer>
    <lesmer intro="Days without work included in the qualifying period">
        <liste>
            <punkt>If you have been working <b>continuously for four weeks</b> and there are no more than <b>fourteen days</b> between each time you are at work, days without work are also included in the qualifying period.</punkt>
            <punkt>If you have an employment agreement for <b>fixed shifts</b>, the days you are not at work will be included in the qualifying period, even if you work less than every 14th day.</punkt>
            <punkt><b>Holidays and time off in lieu</b> are also included.</punkt>
        </liste>
    </lesmer>
</innhold>