<innhold>
    <avsnitt>Fishery workers can receive their pay in a number of different ways. Some people are paid a fixed rate (“hyre”), some are paid as a share of the catch (“lott”), and some receive their pay as a combination of the two. It is important that we receive correct information about your work situation so that we can calculate your parental benefit correctly.</avsnitt>
    <avsnitt><b>Seafarer’s wages (“hyre”)</b></avsnitt>
    <avsnitt>If you receive seafarer’s wages (“hyre” in Norwegian), you are paid as an employee. Not all fishery workers are registered as employed in the National Register of Employers and Employees (the Aa Register), such that it appears in the application. The reason why you cannot see your employment is that your employer is not obliged to register fishery workers as employees.</avsnitt>
    <avsnitt>If you are an employed fishery worker who receives seafarer’s wages (“hyre”), your employer must submit an income report with information about your income. Your employer can read more about submitting income reports and find a guide on <lenke url="https://www.nav.no/no/bedrift/tjenester-og-skjemaer/nav-og-altinn-tjenester/foreldrepenger-og-svangerskapspenger2" ekstern="true">completing them here.</lenke></avsnitt>
    <avsnitt><b>Share of the catch (“lott”)</b></avsnitt>
    <avsnitt>If your pay as a fishery worker is calculated as a share of the catch (“lott” in Norwegian), you are considered self-employed. In this case, in the application dialogue you must answer “yes” when asked whether you are self-employed, and then select “fishery worker” when entering information about your business. The questions you are asked in the application will then be tailored to your situation and you will receive guidance and information as you fill in the form. When you tell us that you are a fishery worker, we can then register the correct information about you, ensuring we send correct information about you to the Tax Administration.</avsnitt>
    <avsnitt>You can read more about pay for fishery workers as a share of the catch (“lott”) and seafarer’s wages (“hyre”) on the <lenke url="https://www.skatteetaten.no/rettskilder/type/handboker/skatte-abc/2019/fiske/F-14.014/F-14.048/" ekstern="true">Norwegian Tax Administration’s website</lenke></avsnitt>
    <avsnitt><b>Fishery worker with own boat</b></avsnitt>
    <avsnitt>If you work as a fishery worker with your own boat, you are considered self-employed. In this case, in the application dialogue you must answer “yes” when asked whether you are self-employed, and then select “fishery worker” when entering information about your business.</avsnitt>
    <avsnitt><b>If you receive a combination of both types of pay</b></avsnitt>
    <avsnitt>If you receive pay as both a share of the catch (“lott”) and seafarer’s wages (“hyre”), you receive income both as an employee and as an independent self-employed person.</avsnitt>
    <avsnitt>For the part of your income that is paid as seafarer’s wages (“hyre”), you are considered an employee, and you receive a salary as an employee.  Not all fishery workers are registered as employed in the National Register of Employers and Employees (the Aa Register), such that it appears in the application. If you are an employed fishery worker who receives seafarer’s wages (“hyre”), your employer must submit an income report with information about your income.</avsnitt>
    <avsnitt>For the part of your income that you receive as a share of the catch (“lott”), you are considered self-employed. In this case, in the application dialogue you must answer “yes” when asked whether you are self-employed, and then select “fishery worker” when entering information about your business. The questions you are asked in the application will then be tailored to your situation and you will receive guidance and information as you fill in the form. When you tell us that you are a fishery worker, we can then register the correct information about you, ensuring we send correct information about you to the Tax Administration.</avsnitt>
    <avsnitt>You can read more about pay for fishery workers as a share of the catch (“lott”) and seafarer’s wages (“hyre”) on the <lenke url="https://www.skatteetaten.no/rettskilder/type/handboker/skatte-abc/2019/fiske/F-14.014/F-14.048/" ekstern="true">Norwegian Tax Administration’s website</lenke></avsnitt>
</innhold>
