<innhold>
    <avsnitt>
        Pregnancy allowance is calculated based on your income. You can get paid pregnancy money up to
        <lenke url="https://www.nav.no/en/NAV+and+Community/Contact+NAV/Payments/Grunnbelopet+i+folketrygden" ekstern="true">
            Six times the basic amount.
        </ lenke>
    </avsnitt>
    <avsnitt>
        <b>
            Employee
        </b>
    </avsnitt>
    <avsnitt>
        Are you
        <b>
            employee
        </b>
        Your pregnancy allowance is usually considered based on the average income you have had in the last three calendar months before you receive your maternity benefit. This applies both if you are a permanent employee or have varying periods of work or income.
        If there is more than 25 percent difference between your annual income and your income over the last three months, we need to consider which income is most representative in your situation.
    </avsnitt>
    <liste>
        <punkt>
            Have your employment been everywhere
            <b>
                for three months
            </b>
            , the pregnancy pens must be calculated based on the income you have had during the period you have been in work. Your income is converted into a monthly income.
        </punkt>
        <punkt>
            Have you had
            <b>
                vacation
            </b>
            or short periods of random unpaid leave during the period you have earned, your income is determined by what you would normally have if you had been in work.
        </punkt>
        <punkt>
            If
            <b>
                Your employment ends
            </b>
            Before you receive a pregnancy allowance, the pregnancy allowance is calculated according to your income the last three months before the employment relationship was terminated.
        </punkt>
    </liste>
    <avsnitt>
        <b>
            Freelancer
        </b>
    </avsnitt>
    <avsnitt>
        Are you
        <b>
            freelancer
        </b>
        Your pregnancy money is usually calculated from the average income you have had in them
        <b>
            last three calendar months
        </b>
        before getting a pregnancy allowance
    </avsnitt>
    <avsnitt>
        If there is more than 25 percent difference between your annual income and your income and your income over the last three months, we need to consider which income is most representative in your situation.
    </avsnitt>
    <liste>
        <punkt>
            If you have worked so shortly that no freelance income has been reported for the three full months to the a-scheme, then the income for this shorter period should be used in the calculation.
        </punkt>
    </liste>
    <avsnitt>
        <b>
            Self-employed
        </b>
        Are you
        <b>
            self-employed
        </b>
        Your pregnancy allowance is usually calculated at the average of your income
        <b>
            Three last years to be finished.
        </b>
    </avsnitt>
    <avsnitt>
        If your business or work situation has changed permanently, the income you have when you start with a pregnancy allowance can be used instead. Income over
        <lenke url ="https://www.nav.no/no/NAV+og+samfunn/Kontakt+NAV/Utbetalinger/Snarveier/satser--380089?kap=383506" ekstern="true">
            12 times the basic amount
        </lenke>
        the National Insurance is not included in the calculation.
    </avsnitt>
</innhold>