<innhold>
    <avsnitt>Pregnancy allowance is calculated based on your income. You can get paid pregnancy allowance up to <lenke url="https://www.nav.no/en/NAV+and+Community/Contact+NAV/Payments/Grunnbelopet+i+folketrygden" ekstern="true">six times the basic amount.</lenke></avsnitt>
    <avsnitt type="element">Employee</avsnitt>
    <avsnitt>If you are an <b>employee</b> your pregnancy allowance is usually calculated based on your average income over the past three calendar months before you receive your pregnancy allowance. This applies either if you are a permanent employee or have had infrequent periods of work or income. If there is more than 25 per cent difference between your annual income and your income over the last three months, we need to consider which income is most representative in your situation.
        If there is more than 25 per cent difference between your annual income and your income over the last three months, we need to consider which income is most representative in your situation.</avsnitt>
    <liste>
        <punkt>If you have been in employment <b> for less than</b> three months your pregnancy allowance will be calculated based on the income you have had for the duration of your employment. Your income will be converted into a monthly income.</punkt>
        <punkt>If you have been on <b>vacation</b> or have had short periods of random, unpaid leave during the timeframe used to calculate your earnings, your income for those periods will be determined to be what you would have normally earned in those periods.</punkt>
    </liste>
    <avsnitt type="element">Freelancer</avsnitt>
    <avsnitt>Your pregnancy allowance will be calculated on the basis of the average of the income that you have had in the  <b>last three calendar months</b> before the start of your pregnancy allowance period.</avsnitt>
    <avsnitt>If the difference between your annual income and your income in the past three months is greater than 25 per cent, we must assess which income is most representative in your situation.</avsnitt>
    <liste>
        <punkt>If you have been working for such a short period that no freelance income has been reported to the a-ordningen for three full months, the income for this shorter period of time will be used in the calculations.</punkt>
    </liste>
    <avsnitt type="element">Self-employed</avsnitt>
    <avsnitt>If you are <b>self-employed</b> your pregnancy allowance is usually calculated as the average of your income in <b> the last three years for which tax has been assessed.</b></avsnitt>
    <avsnitt>If your business or work situation has changed permanently, the income you had when you start with your pregnancy allowance can be used instead. Income over<lenke url ="https://www.nav.no/no/NAV+og+samfunn/Kontakt+NAV/Utbetalinger/Snarveier/satser--380089?kap=383506" ekstern="true"> six times</lenke> the National Insurance basic amount("G") is not included in the calculation.</avsnitt>
</innhold>
