<innhold>
    <avsnitt>You may apply for parental benefit when you know the date of <b>assumption of care</b>.</avsnitt>
    </lesmer>
    <avsnitt>To apply, log in using your BankID system from your bank or another approved electronic ID. The questions asked in the application are adapted to your situation, and instructions and information are provided as you fill in the form.</avsnitt>
    <avsnitt>In the application you will be asked to enclose documentation of assumption of care.</avsnitt>
    <lesmer liten="true" intro="Have you received a severance package, interim pay or been in compulsory military service?">
        <avsnitt>You must submit documentation of your income and the period if you have had one of these sources of income:</avsnitt>
        <liste>
            <punkt>compulsory military service or Norwegian Civil Defence</punkt>
            <punkt>severance package</punkt>
            <punkt>salary from employer during further or continuing education</punkt>
            <punkt>interim pay or allowance</punkt>
        </liste>
    </lesmer>
        <lesmer liten="true" intro="Will you be receiving parental benefit in the shared period?">
        <avsnitt>You must provide documentation of father 1’s activity requirement if you are staying at home during the shared period. He must either:</avsnitt>
        <liste>
            <punkt>be employed</punkt>
            <punkt>study full-time</punkt>
            <punkt>combine studying with work that together makes it full-time</punkt>
            <punkt>be fully dependent on assistance to take care of the child due to sickness</punkt>
            <punkt>be hospitalised at a hospital or health care institution</punkt>
            <punkt>participate in a qualification programme</punkt>
            <punkt>participate full-time in the Introduction Programme for newly arrived immigrants pursuant to chapter 2 of the Introduction Act</punkt>
        </liste>
    </lesmer>
    <søkKnapp søknad="parental benefit">Apply now</søkKnapp>
</innhold>
